Mss.B.W243 Mss.B.W243
American Philosophical Society
- Papers, 1850-1864
  - Letter to John Warner, June 6, 1862; 5" x 8"; Indiana University
    Bloomington, Ind. A.L.S: Daniel Kirkwood, sec. of the faculty. 1p. Thanks for the box of models illustrative of Warner's Treatise on earthwork, presented by the author.
  - Letter to John Warner, June 7, 1862; 5" x 8"; Kirkwood, Daniel, 1814-1895
    A.L.S. 2p. Appreciation for the models presented by Mr. Warner. Will recommend his book.
  - Letter to M. de Franqueville, Director of Ponts et Chaussées, Dec. 3, 1863; 8 1/4" x 13"; Warner, John, -1873
    Paris, A.Dr. of L.S. 2p. Is the author of a work and inventor of an instrument designed to assist the cubature of railroad excavations and embankments; submits these with the request that they be examined by the Commission des inventions de l'Ecole des ponts et chaussées.
  - Letter to Prof. Mangon, Dec. 3, 1863; 8" x 10"; Warner, John, -1873
    Paris, A.Dr. of L.S. 1p. and end. Thanks him for the trouble he has taken on Warner's behalf relative to his work on earthwork.
  - Letter to the Minister of public works, Dec. 18, 1863; 8 1/2" x 12 1/2"; Warner, John, -1873
    Paris, A.Dr. of L. 1p. In pencil. Is the author of a work and inventor of an instrument designed to assist the cubature of railroad excavations and embankments; has left copies of his work and the instrument, and asks that they be given and examination by the Commission des inventions des Ponts et chaussées.
  - Letter to John Warner, Jan. 9, 1864; 8 1/4" x 12"; France. Ministre de l'agriculture, du commerce et des travaux publics
    Paris, L.S: In French. In accordance with his request has transmitted his letter and invention to M. Avril, inspector general of Ponts et Chaussées.
- John Warner diaries, 1862-1868, B W243d; 52.0 Volume(s); 52 volumes, circa 2600 p.; These pocket-sized volumes detail Warner's travels through Europe, Asia, and parts of Africa, and include interesting sketches scattered throughout the volumes. The diaries from these travels also include 23 maps.; 52 volumes, ca. 2600 p.; Warner, John,d. 1873. (Volume 52)
  General note
  See Murphy D. Smith, "Historical American Sketches. An Illustrated Guide to Sketches in the Manuscript Collections of the American Philosophical Society" (Boston, 1984): 242-243.
  Other Finding Aids note
  Realms of Gold, 52.
  Africa--Description and travel; Asia -- Description and travel.; Diaries.; Europe -- Description and travel.; Sketches.